自动字幕整理+翻译：Superbart 原作者LGR发布于2021年4月22日
字幕下载：github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles
支持原作者：patreon.com/LazyGameReviews​
Greetings, welcome to a blurbs video.
大家好，我又来随便说说了
And another one here, in the WinRAR saga, I assume.
这回呢，我猜这个包裹又是一个WinRAR相关
Anyway, I don't know precisely what is in this because,
说真的，我都不知道这个包裹里面装着什么
I was contacted by someone that works for Cleverbridge, or with them.
当我浏览我Pateron页面的时候
And uh, yeah, I was actually an LGR Pateron.
有个在Cleverbridge工作的人联系了我
They did get in touch when I did my original WinRAR registration video over on LGR.
实际上，他们在我上传WinRAR激活视频后就找到我了
And then, when I mentioned that I ordered a physical copy of it,
我在视频中提到我订了实体版后
they're like "Oh hey! Yeah, I'm working with a Cleverbridge myself."
那家伙说：“我在Cleverbridge工作。”
So it was kind of wild to see that mentioned.
突然一看还挺让我难以置信
So they got in touch again and said:
这回，他们又联系我说
"Hey, what's what's your order number? Let me just check something.
“你的订单号多少？我看看有啥好的（给你寄过去）。
"And you know, maybe keep an eye out in your mailbox."
”当然，注意你家的信箱哦。“
And well, here it is! Whatever it is...
然后，这就是了，不管是啥了:-|
It's from Cleverbridge, a different address than last time, I believe.
这是从Cleverbridge发货的，不过应该不是上回的地址
So yeah, let me just go ahead and open this up, and we'll see what we've got going on.
现在，咱来拆包，看看有啥吧
I'm assuming WinRAR related, but I just don't know. So...
我猜跟WinRAR有关，但不确定，那么......
Whoa! What in the world?
等会，这嘛玩意？
Look at that! No way!
我没看错吧！
I... was genuinely not expecting a floppy disk.
我从没想过这回是张软盘
WinRAR version 2.0, 2021? Em, is serious? Oh man.
WinRAR 2.0版本，版权2021? 我没穿越吧？ 天啊
"The team at RARLAB and cleverbridge thought this idea is both weird and funny."
"RARLAB和Cleverbridge觉得这个想法怪异可笑"
Yes, it is. "So we rolled with it. Now it's a one off 'thing'.
确实如此，"我们就这么做了，就是这个唯一的恼人的小玩意
off的形容词意思有：不愉快的，不新鲜的，远处的，错位的等
"This thing might fit well in the 'Diskette Holder'."
"这玩意可以放进 'Diskette Holder'."
You bet it will! And the diskette holder they're referring to...
这可你说的啊！而他们说的Diskette Holder是指......
is this lovely thing, I assume.
我猜是这玩意
I did a video on this as well, here on blurbs.
我曾经也在随心说频道说过这个
Not too long after, or before, or something.
也就最近几期吧
When I did the WinRAR stuff...
那是我在做WinRAR啥的......
So yeah, checking out. had a got a holder right here doing...
好的，我手里拿着软盘了
And now we have a diskette holder, for WinRAR only.
我也为WinRAR软盘特地拿出这个收纳盒了
And I guess I can put the uh, the little note down here in the label holder.
我觉得我可以在底下放一张标签纸吧
Why not, right? Uh, thank you, Nick!
我觉得还行。无论如何，感谢Nick
And everybody else involved at RARLAB, cleverbridge...
和在RARLAB，cleverbridge里走心的人
The fact that, this is turning into just an ongoing thing.
实际上，我觉得WinRAR这事要没完了
I've gotten so many emails, and tweets, and other social media posts and things
我从我的电邮，人人网(雾)啥的看到很多人说
about just people saying "Oh yeah, I've now registered WinRAR.
“啊，我也注册了WinRAR.
SuperBart：强烈建议大家不要将钱浪费在此以及各种dark♂公司。
花在有意义的地方，或是考虑一下给我们搬运工打赏吧:-)
"And I got my own physical copy through cleverbridge." And whatever.
我也从cleverbridge那收到了我的实体版。”啥的
Just like, you know. I mean, come on, it's 2021, is the year the WinRAR registration.
有点那啥，现在是2021年，是注册WinRAR的一年呢
That is wonderful. The fact that, they actually went out of their way to get a floppy disk.
而这真是挺好的，他们做这个玩意挺费事的
go out of their way: (为帮助别人)花费比预想的很多很多的精力
And because they don't offer this, this is not a service they offer.
并且他们也没有提供软盘的服务
Like I said, it's a "one off".
他们也说，这是“唯一”的
But you know, anything that I've ever seen that gets registered through cleverbridge,
但是呢，我是从cleverbridge拿到的软件
you know, like one of the companies that use them
也是，很多公司委托他们分发实体版注册软件
sending out physical copies of registered programs.
They're all CDs, and they're all pretty basic.
他们都是CD，十分普通的CD
Yeah, this is on another level.
然后，这就有点独特了
And the fact, that is 2.0.
实际上，这里面是2.0版本的
uh... All right, let's check it out. And see if it is indeed that. 2002...
好吧，咱来看看吧，看看这玩意到底是不是
All right, so I got Windows 98 going here.
好的，我的Windows 98电脑开机了
Assuming if it is 2.0, that this will be just fine.
要真是2.0版本的话，那就好了
It is got the registration information.
这里有注册信息
Oh man, it's personalized.
天哪，居然提到我的名字
"Hello LGR" Wow, how special.
"您好，LGR：" 哇，真是走心了:-)
Got the jpeg there, for the html notes for registering.
有张图片，用在解释注册的html文件中
Yeah, that's just information license and whatnot, which is good.
就是些注册信息，用户协议啥的，挺好的
开源宣传时间，大家可以暂停一下看看
God of FPS John Carmack at Quake Source Code:
因为最近以来社区的巨大损失，尤其是某些对代码的修改保持闭源（甚至有丢失的）
如果你想共享你对源代码的修改的话，你必须要开源你的代码
Because this version of it does not use the WinRAR key file.
因为这个版本的WinRAR无法使用密钥文件
So it's just a regular old classic WinRAR, you gotta register it manually.
就是一个经典的老版本WinRAR，你必须手动注册
Let me make sure I don't already have it on here. I don't think I do.
我看看我有没有安装，应该是没有的
Oh yeah, load that off of floppy.
好的，现在从软盘上加载中
Oh yes, dude. This is really like...
好吧，看上去有点......
it's so simple but it's a nice gesture and it's an extremely novel thing to
安装界面简单直接，在2021年仍能收到
just get a registered WinRAR floppy disk in 2021.
注册版的WinRAR软盘也真是挺新鲜的
Through... pretty much the most official channel you can.
尤其是......更多是因为这是官方渠道吧
Oh yes.
<(￣︶￣)>
And there we go, WinRAR 95 and the 3.1 interface. Since it installs both of those by default.
好的，95界面和3.1界面都装上了，本来默认是这样的
We'll go with the 95 here, evaluation copy.
好的，这是95界面，评估副本
Yep, time to register this.
好的，该注册了
I mean, it's just registering WinRAR.
没错，这就注册完了
It's nothing we haven't seen before already
前两期视频我们可是将这个过程融化在血液中的每一部分了
a couple of times now on LGR things in the recent past.
Yeah, there's an effort that went (into) this.
他们可是花了很多心思
It is highly appreciated and what a neat little collectible kind of a...
我十分高兴，能有这个有收藏价值的软盘
a bookend to this whole trek of registering this classic program
用来激活这个经典软件的超老版本
that pretty much no one ever bought and registered back in the day, at least.
至少在当时可真是没多少人会这么做啊
So goes the legend obviously it's become clear that tons of people did,
不过很明显，在很长的一段时间里，还是有很多人这么做的
SuperBart: 支持正版，从我做起！反对专利版权流氓，从我做起！
and people still are doing so.
现在仍有人正在那么做
Just judging by all the comments and messages I've gotten.
这是我看了很多的评论和私信后的一点感想
It's just more of a meme at this point, and...
在当时有点像是梗，而且呢......
I mean, why not ride the wave a little bit by sending out a floppy disk?
为何不再送张软盘，给这个梗的宣传来点力度呢？
Very, very cool. Thank you Nick, and the rest of the folks involved.
真的非常非常不错，感谢Nick和那些走心的人
This is just a lot of fun.
真的乐趣很多
And made for a fun little blurb. Thanks for watching!
我做这期随心说也很开心，感谢收看！